So here we have our skeleton code for the PokemonApp.
لدينا هنا الكود الهيكلي لتطبيق PokemonApp.
If we go into app, source, main,
إذا دخلنا إلى app، ثم src، ثم main،
java, we have two Java files.
ثم java، فسنجد ملفين لـJava.
MainActivity and HttpHandler.
ملف MainActivity وHttpHandler.
Let's look at the MainActivity file first.
لنلقي نظرة على ملف MainActivity أولاً.
The first thing to notice is that you'll see
أول شيء ستلاحظه هو أنك سترى
a few red lines in the code, but don't worry.
بضعة خطوط حمراء في الكود. لكن لا تقلق،
As soon as you finish this practice set those lines should go away.
حالما تكمل مجموعة التمارين هذه، ستختفي تلك الخطوط.
We see that there is a GetPokemon class with a doInBackground at it.
نرى أن هناك فئة GetPokemon مع أسلوب doInBackground.
We have an HttpHandler and a string url with this link. Let's click on it.
لدينا HttpHandler وسلسلة url مع هذا الرابط. لننقر عليه.
So, here we have the JSON data for each Pokemon,
لدينا هنا بيانات JSON لكل بوكيمون،
and each Pokemon will have its respective unique attributes.
وسيكون لكل بوكيمون سمات فريدة به.
So for example, it will have an integer attribute called id,
فسيكون له مثلاً سمة عدد صحيح تُسمى "id"،
a string attribute called num and a couple other attributes.
وسمة سلسلة تدعى "num" وبعض السمات الأخرى.
There is also an attribute type with an array that holds several strings.
هناك أيضاً نوع من السمات يأتي مع مصفوفة ويحتوي على عدة سلاسل.
The thing to notice here is that each Pokemon will have a different set of attributes.
الأمر الواجب ملاحظته هو أنه سيكون لكل بوكيمون مجموعة مختلفة من السمات،
And we'll be using its attributes to display in our app.
وسنستخدم تلك السمات لعرضها في تطبيقنا.
Going back to the MainActivity.
لنعد إلى نافذة MainActivity.
Let's keep going. There are several TODO tasks for you to do.
لنتابع. هناك العديد من مهام TODO التي عليك القيام بها.
So just make a request to the URL and create a new JSONObject.
مثل تقديم طلب للـurl وإنشاء JSONObject جديد.
There's also a for loop that will go through all the Pokemons
هنالك أيضاً حلقة for ستمر على جميع البوكيمونات،
and put them in a list that we'll be using to display over here.
وتضعها في قائمة سنستخدمها للعرض هنا.
Next, let's look at our HttpHandler file.
لنلقي نظرة على ملف HttpHandler.
Here, there is a method called makeHttpRequest and we will pass in the URL.
يوجد هنا أسلوب يسمى makeHttpRequest، وسنمرره على الـurl.
Here is where we make the request to make a connection with the URL.
وهنا هو المكان الذي نطلب فيه إنشاء اتصال مع الـurl.
Next, let's look in the res file and layout.
لننظر تالياً في ملف res، في layout.
These files are provided for you,
تم تزويدك بهذه الملفات
so you don't have to worry about how to display each Pokemon.
كي لا تقلق من كيفية عرض كل بوكيمون.
This is a simple list format that will display each Pokemon.
هذا تنسيق قائمة بسيط يعرض كل بوكيمون.
And this is what each list item will have.
وهذا ما سيحتويه كل عنصر في القائمة.
There is a box for a name,
هناك صندوق لاسم
an id and a candy.
ولمعرّف ولحلوى.
These files will organize the information you're parsing into a simple list format.
ستنظم هذه الملفات المعلومات التي تحللها إلى تنسيق قائمة بسيط.
So in the next few sections,
ففي الأقسام القليلة التالية،
we'll be fill in these blanks to
سنملأ هذه الفراغات
list out all of the Pokemons with three of their attributes.
لإدخال جميع البوكيمونات في قائمة مع ثلاثة من سماتها.
Their name, their id and their candy.
اسمها ومعرّفها والحلوى التي تأكلها.
This is what the final product should look like.
هكذا ينبغي أن يبدو المنتج الأخير.
You will see that the name is at the top. So, Bulbasaur.
سترى أن الاسم في الأعلى. إذن، "بلباسور".
This is their id and this is their candy.
هذا معرّفه، وهذه الحلوى الخاصة به.
And if I scroll down,
وإن مررت إلى الأسفل،
you'll find that each Pokemon will have different attributes.
ستجد أن لكل بوكيمون سمات مختلفة. 00:02:44,932 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 لنبدأ إذن.